corel.com 2018-04-02

# Corel Privacy Policy | Legal Information

At Corel, we recognize and value our customers' privacy. As such, Corel is committed to ensuring that its customers are informed how their personal information will be used and kept secure. This privacy policy applies to information collected by Corel and its affiliates (“Corel”) through the websites, products and services that display this privacy policy, including products and services that may be provided by Corel off-line. This privacy policy applies to all Corel products and services currently offered by Corel.

Corel will not contact you for marketing purposes unless you have opted to be contacted. You can change your preferences about receiving marketing communications from us at any time by signing into your account through our website using your credentials (email address and password) and clicking on “Manage Your Communications Preferences.”

Except as set forth in Section 2, Section 6, Section 7 and Section 16 of this privacy policy, Corel will not share any of your personal information with third parties without first obtaining your consent.

**BY VISITING COREL'S WEBSITES, OR BY USING OR PURCHASING THE PRODUCTS AND SERVICES OFFERED BY COREL, YOU ACCEPT THE PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND CONSENT TO COREL'S USE OF YOUR INFORMATION IN THE MANNER DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

### 1\. INFORMATION THAT COREL COLLECTS

Corel may collect information about you your identity and personal preferences as they relate to our products. Personal information we may typically collect includes your name, postal address, email address, telephone number, IP address and, in relation to purchases you may make, your credit card information. Corel will try to collect only information that is necessary for the purpose Corel is collecting the information. For example, if you purchase a Corel product, we will require you to disclose your name and address (so that we can send the product to you) and your credit card details (to obtain payment). Our objective is to inform you before or at the time of collection what information we will collect and why and how we will use it. If we require additional specific personal information from you, we will use reasonable commercial efforts to inform you at the time of collection about the information we need to collect, the purposes for which it is being collected and how the information will be used, so that you can make an informed decision about whether to provide it. If you choose not to provide requested information, Corel may not be able to comply with your request or provide certain services.

There are a number of different ways that Corel receives and collects personal information from you. These may include:

###### Communications From You

When you email or write to us, you may provide us with your name, contact details, and other personal information in your message.

###### Customer Support

You may provide us with personal information when you telephone or email us to request technical assistance with our products or information that you would like to receive about them.

###### Email/Direct Mail Campaigns That You Approved

From time to time we may contact you directly by mail, email or telephone informing you about upgrades, new products, promotions or special offers that you told us you were interested in receiving. When responding to one of these campaigns, you may provide us with personal information. If you want to stop receiving promotional and information materials from us, you can follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email, contact us at privacy@corel.com or change your preferences by signing into your account through our website using your credentials (email address and password) and clicking on “Manage Your Communications Preferences.”

###### Registration of Products

Upon registration of a Corel product, you will be asked to provide information that we will use to record you as an owner of a Corel product and to assist us in providing you with service and information.

###### Installation and Use of Products

When you install and use Corel products, we may use information about your browser type, operating system, hardware, other software on your system, IP address and the functions of the Corel products and services that you use so that we can facilitate, evaluate and verify your use of our products and services.

###### Purchases

If you wish to purchase Corel products from our eStore or over the telephone we will require sufficient information to complete your purchase including your credit card and shipping information.

###### Resumes

We obtain your personal information when you apply and/or submit your resume for an employment opportunity at Corel, but we will only use this information to evaluate your potential employment with us.

###### Surveys

From time to time we may conduct surveys in respect of our products and services. Participation in our surveys is optional. However, if you respond to one of our surveys, you may provide us with personal information about you. Unless you otherwise consent, we will only use this information to determine the types of offers, products or services that may be of interest to you and to operate and improve our product and services offerings.

### 2\. PURPOSES FOR WHICH COREL USES INFORMATION

Corel may use your personal information for the following purposes:

###### Product Registration

Information you provide upon registration will be used to keep a record of your product license and will assist Corel in providing support to you when you contact Corel's customer service department. Corel will also use this information to inform you of any upgrades, new products, promotions or other information that may be of interest to you.

###### Product Installation and Use

Information gathered during installation may be used by Corel to (i) authenticate and periodically verify your licensing rights in the product for anti-piracy purposes (ii) identify if new product updates are available for your computer prior to sending you a notice to install the new product update; and (iii) receive in-product messages from Corel that you have requested to receive.

###### Product Purchases

When you purchase products from Corel's eStore or directly from Corel's customer service department, Corel will use your information to process payment and ship the product to you.

###### Newsletters

We may use your personal information to send you newsletters that provide you with articles and information that we believe may be of interest to you.

###### Information About Corel Products

It is important for us to receive feedback from our customers about our products and any features they would like to see in future products. As such, we may use your personal information to contact you about our products and to inform you of upgrades, promotions and new products that may be of interest to you.

###### Internal Analysis

We may use the information you provide us with for our own internal statistical and analytical purposes, to evaluate and enhance users' experience of the Site by identifying customer preferences and purchasing trends that we may use for marketing purposes and in respect of operations and development.

###### Updating information

We may contact you to ensure that the information we have in our records is still correct, to add additional information or to communicate with you about an outstanding transaction.

###### Special Collaborative Programs

We may collaborate with another company to provide you with a unique product or service (a “Collaborative Program”). The use of your information by Corel and its collaborators is limited to the specific Collaborative Program that you have joined or elected to use. By using a Collaborative Program, you have given Corel and the collaborating company permission to collect information and provide you with updates, promotions and new Collaborative Program product or service information relating only to the Collaborative Program. To the extent personal information is collected by a third-party collaborator, we will use reasonable commercial efforts to advise you of this fact, and all information collected by such collaborator will be governed by the collaborator's privacy policy.

### 3\. AUTOMATICALLY COLLECTED INFORMATION

Whenever you enter our website or access any on-line information through a Corel product, our web server automatically collects and aggregates information (“Automatic Information”) in respect of your visit. Automatic Information may include URLs or domains of referring websites, browser type, operating system, the pages that you access and the date and time of your visit. Automatic Information collected by Corel is used for statistical and marketing purposes.

We use Automatic Information to help us improve our understanding of our users and their preferences. We also use it to assist us in arranging relevant advertising, commercial opportunities and competitions. Automatic Information we collect also helps us to develop our website and audit its use. Furthermore, Corel may share Automatic Information with its co-branding partners in order to improve the content, banners and promotions that you and other users will see on our websites and in our products.

### 4\. USER FILES

In addition, certain of our products may allow you to store, send, receive, edit, sync, share, or otherwise organize or manage files and folders (including any information or data stored in those folders) (“User Files”). We may record and store information regarding the size and name of all User Files that you make available via these products. Because the names of the User Files you submit are not treated as personal information, we recommend that you do not include any non-public personal information to describe User Files that you make available via these products and services.

### 5\. FACEBOOK CONNECT

Corel offers Facebook users the opportunity to interact with their friends and share information on Facebook using Facebook Connect. If you elect to link your account with us with your Facebook account, you grant us permission to post information to your Facebook account and to access your Facebook profile information, and to use this information in accordance with this privacy policy. Please refer to Facebook's privacy policy for information concerning how Facebook handles your personal information and to the privacy settings in your Facebook account to manage your preferences relating to your Facebook account.

### 6\. SHARING OF INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

Except as specifically described in Section 2, this Section 6, Section 7 and Section 16, Corel will not share any personal information with third parties without obtaining your consent (e.g. through an option via your user account).

###### Affiliates and Subsidiaries

We may share the information that you have provided to us with subsidiaries and affiliated companies of Corel Corporation who are required to comply with the terms of this policy.

###### Internal Operations

We may also share information that you have provided to us with independent auditors, acting on our behalf, for anti-piracy and revenue accounting purposes in connection with the internal operations of our business, provided that such companies comply with the terms of this policy.

###### Promotional Offers

As a registered Corel customer, you have the opportunity to receive news and special offers from Corel and certain third parties who we think may offer products or services that would be of interest to you. If you have provided us with consent we may send you applicable news and special offers and share your personal information with these third parties so that they may send you information about their products and services directly.

###### Service Providers

We occasionally hire other companies to provide services on our behalf, such as processing transactions, including credit card transactions, handling the processing and delivery or mailings, providing customer support, hosting websites, collecting, storing or removing your information, or performing statistical analysis of our products or services. We sometimes need to share your information with these other companies in order for them to provide the applicable services, such as sharing your information with our third party e-commerce provider to process your purchase transactions. These companies are only provided with the information that is necessary for them to provide the services and they are not authorized by us to use your information for any purpose other than delivering the services that have been requested by Corel in accordance with Corel's instructions and policies.

### 7\. LEGAL DISCLOSURE

Although we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or other legal process or to protect Corel's, our users' or third parties' rights, property or safety.

### 8\. SECURITY

We maintain reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. While no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure from intrusion, we have used and will continue to use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the protection of your personal information.

### 9\. ENCRYPTION

Orders received by the Corel eStore (including credit card information) are encrypted using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) Protocol for browsers that supports 128 bit encryption.

### 10\. COOKIES

A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser of your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are and other details. Cookies may be set by a website or originate with third parties, such as advertisers. A cookie itself is not designed or intended to read any information from a user's computer (other than the contents of the cookie). A cookie is simply an identifier used by the website that originally placed it on your hard drive. The actual contents of the cookie information can be retrieved by the same server to identify the computer and subsequently to customize, track, or regulate the use of a site based on information stored on the host server.

We may make use of cookies on our website. We use cookies to allow us to automate the access and the data entry functions of our website and to correlate online ordering information for purchases you may make while at the website (if any), tailor our website to your preferences or interests, or customize promotions or marketing. In addition, cookies allow us to track use of our website to determine those areas which are useful or popular and those that are not thereby enabling us to improve and update our website effectively. Approved advertising partners or other online services collaborators from Collaborative Programs may use their own cookies.

Most web browsers can either alert you to the use of cookies or refuse to accept cookies entirely. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of the website if cookies are disabled.

For more information on how to disable cookies you should consult the documentation or instructions that accompanied your web browser or by visiting the Federal Trade Commission's website at <http://www.ftc.gov/ftc/cookies.shtm>.

We do not use flash cookies.

Mixpanel: We use Mixpanel as our primary analytic tool to understand how our customers use our products and services. This helps us, for example, build a better application experience for our customers. You can read the [MixPanel Privacy Policy](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/) and [opt-out here](https://mixpanel.com/optout/).

NOTE: If your default browser is not Internet Explorer, please be advised you will need to to visit the opt-out page using Internet Explorer to opt-out of product tracking. <https://mixpanel.com/optout/>

### 11\. LINKS

We may offer links from our website to other websites (which may be hosted by third parties that we choose to offer co-branded products with or by unrelated companies) which we think may be of interest to you. Third party websites are not governed by this privacy policy and Corel makes no representation as to their practices for dealing with your personal information. We recommend that you check the privacy policy of any website at the beginning of your visit to determine its practices.

### 12\. CHAT ROOMS, NEWGROUPS, BLOGS AND OTHER INTERACTIVE LOCATIONS

Corel's website may have chat rooms, newsgroups, blogs, or other forums that permit individuals to interact online. Some of these forums may allow you to post a profile picture, share your gender and age and display your user name or real name (if you choose to display it). Any information you post in online forums will be made public and Corel cannot control nor is it responsible for the use any third parties may make of this information.

### 13\. CHILDREN

Corel's website is a general audience site that is neither designed nor intended to collect personal information from children who are under the age of 13. Corel does not sell products for purchase by children. We sell children's products for purchase by adults. We do not knowingly request personal information from anyone under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. To ensure compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, children under the age of 13 should not access this site or provide any personal information to this site. We encourage parents and guardians to supervise and join their children in exploring the Internet and to help us protect their privacy by instructing them not to provide personal information over the Internet without parental permission. Parents should additionally be aware of a growing variety of software capable of filtering online information to reflect their own choices and guidelines. If we become aware that a user is under the age of 13 and has provided personal information to us without prior verifiable parental consent, we will remove such personal information from our records.

### 14\. ACCESS, MODIFICATION AND ACCURACY OF INFORMATION

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the information that we receive from you is accurate and kept up to date. You have the right to access your personal information, to verify its accuracy, and to correct inaccurate information. You can change your preferences at any time by signing into your account through our website with your credentials (email address and password) and clicking on “Your Account Information.” You can also access and correct errors in your personal information by contacting us at [privacy@corel.com](mailto:privacy@corel.com).

If you do not want to be contacted for product, service or marketing initiatives, or if you would like to be removed from any direct marketing initiatives, corporate surveys, telemarketing or direct mail or e-mail lists, or if you would otherwise like to limit our use or disclosure of your personal information, please contact us at [privacy@corel.com](mailto:privacy@corel.com) or change your preferences by signing into your account through our website using your credentials (email address and password) and clicking on “Manage Your Communications Preferences.”

Some of our products display dynamic on-line communications (for example, through a message center), and you may elect not to receive these communications (e.g. such as product updates) by altering your message preferences in the specific product. However, any alterations you make to these product-specific message preferences will not change your general user preferences with regard to the collection and use of your personal information by Corel. Alternatively, altering your general user preferences with regard to the collection and use of your personal information by Corel will not change your product-specific message preferences.

### 15\. RETENTION AND STORAGE OF INFORMATION

We will not retain your information for longer than is necessary for us to use it for the purposes for which it has been collected, unless otherwise required by law or because of pending litigation. When information is no longer required, we will ensure that all such data is removed from our database. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

As noted above in Section 6, we may use the services of third party companies to physically collect, store or remove your information on our behalf. Any such companies will have to comply with the terms of this policy.

### 16\. BUSINESS TRANSFERS

The information that is collected by Corel is considered to be an asset. In the event that Corel, any affiliated company, division or portions of its assets are acquired by another company, such information may be one of the transferred assets. If so, the acquiring company may only use your information in ways consistent with this privacy policy (or any subsequent policy in effect at the time information is collected from you). We note that information submitted or collected after a transfer may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by the successor company.

### 17\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you are a resident of the State of California, under the California Civil Code, you have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, the law provides that if a company has a privacy policy that gives either an opt-out or opt-in choice for use of your personal information by third parties (such as advertisers) for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.

Corel qualifies for the alternative option; it provides you with details on how you may either opt-out or opt-in to the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your personal information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

### 18\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER

Your information may be transferred to and stored on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside of Canada and choose to provide information to us, you should be aware that Corel may transfer your personal information to Canada and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to such transfer.

### 19\. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

We are always looking for ways to improve our business and our practices. Consequently, our policies will continue to evolve. As such, Corel reserves the right to alter this privacy policy from time to time. Changes to this policy will be posted to our Corel.com website. We encourage you to visit our privacy page from time to time to view our most current privacy policy. If we make material changes to this privacy policy that expand our rights to use your personal information, we will notify you and seek your consent through email or a prominent posting on our website.

### 20\. CONTACT US

Any requests for access to your information, modification of your information or questions in respect of this policy should be sent to the following email address [privacy@corel.com](mailto:privacy@corel.com).

Corel offers you other methods to opt out of receiving communications generated by Corel. For example, you may “unsubscribe” from emails by following the process listed in the email to unsubscribe. You can also change your customer profile on the Corel website to indicate that you no longer wish to receive certain information from Corel by signing into your account through our website using your credentials (email address and password) and clicking on “Manage Your Communications Preferences.”

Last Updated: August 2011
